# Supun Praneeth

# Software Engineer



# **Summery**

I enjoy turning complex problems into simple and beautiful codes. I started coding 10 years ago when I was in school and I have 4 years of professional experience in creating web based projects in multiple industries such as leisure, education, travel etc. I am eager to learn new technologies and currently learning NodeJs(Express, Meteor, Sail.Js) and Python. I am also a big fan of open-source development and looking forward to work on open source projects.



# Experience

2016-08 Present

## Tech Lead

Apple Tech Labs

## Responsibilities:

- Design, develop, test and implement new applications.
- Train interns.
- Clearly and regularly communicate with management and technical support colleagues.
- Managing servers (e-mail, database and web servers).
- Design and update software database.
- Analyze user requirements and convert requirements to design documents.

2014-10-2015-08

# Developer

Apple Holidays

## Responsibilities:

- Develop, test and implement new applications.
- Customizing systems/application made by company.
- Design and update software database.



# **Latest Projects**

2016-08 Present

## Real Time Holidays Package Creator (V2)

Web application that creates holiday packages for multiple countries including Sri Lanka, Malaysia, Indonesia, Thailand and Singapore. See full details at: supun.xyz

## Task:

- Planning destinations, shortest path, nearest airports etc.
- Booking cheapest hotels and own accommodations.
- Booking restaurants.
- Driver registration and allocation.

2018 Present

#### Leaflet Bezier

Leaflet: Draws a Bézier line between two points with an animated flight object.





# Personal Info

#### Phone

(+94) 774 637514

#### **Portfolio**

supun.xyz

## E-mail

hello@supun.xyz

## Date of birth

1991-04-12

## Marital status

Single

#### Github

github.com/spmsupun

#### LinkedIn

LinkedIn.com/in/spmsupun

## Stackoverflow

stackoverflow.com/cv/supun



# Skills

PHP (Laravel)

Javascript (ES6)

CSS/SCSS





2018 Present

# **JSQL**

PHP package(Composer) that convert Json object to SQL with relationships.



# **Education**

2014 Present

# **Bachelor of Computer Science**

Following BSC CS at National School of Business Management (NSBM) which is affiliated with University College Dublin (UCD) in Ireland.



# Languages

## **English**

Intermediate

## Sinhala

Native



# References

# Thiraj priyadharshana

Software Engineer 121 Hunupitiya Lake Rd, Colombo 02, Sri Lanka thirajpriyadharshana@gmail.com (+94) 714 542601

## Desmond Bartholomeusz

Senior Manager - Development 148, Aluthmawatha Road, Colombo 15, Sri Lanka product@appleholidaysds.com (+94) 703 653343



# Frameworks / Tools

#### Laravel 5+

2+ year experience

## jQuery

7+ years experience

## Bootstrap 3/4

2+ years experience

## Angular 5+

Learning

# Express.js 4

Learning

## **PhpStorm**

1+ year experience

## Linux (SSH)

1+ year experience

#### GIT

2+ year experience

## Docker

6 months experience

## **AWS**

Learning